Aizza Asuncion

CURRICULUM VITAE

aizzakatrina@zoho.com aizzakatrina.com

SUMMARY

A financial data analyst with a background in accounting, and experience in data/quantitative analysis and financial reporting. Strong knowledge of databases, information systems, and business processes with a track-record for adhering to deadlines. Demonstrated ability to explore, interpret, and extract value from data enabling effective strategic planning in business operations.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certification. University of California, Berkeley. 2018 B.A. Economics, with Accounting concentration. California State University, East Bay. 2016

SKILLS

Financial reporting and modeling, GAAP, Data analytics and visualization, Regression analysis, Machine learning, Root cause analysis, Web scraping

Programming Languages: VBA, SQL, Python, C++, R, Mongo, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Software: Advanced Excel (vlookups, nested functions, charts and graphs, pivot tables), Tableau, NetSuite, Jupyter Notebook

Related Coursework: Intro to Statistics, Econometrics, Economics of Information and Organization (Game Theory), Managerial Economics, Managerial Accounting, Cost Management, Advanced Financial Accounting, International Finance, Industrial Organization, Accounting Information Systems

ANALYTICS DEVELOPMENT

Live Earthquakes Map - A map of fault lines and earthquakes around the world in the past 30 days, updated every 15 minutes. aizzakatrina.com/earthquakes_map

Equatorial Latitude - Data visualizations of the weather of 500 random cities across the world and of varying distances from the equator. aizzakatrina.com/equatorial_latitude

@iPlotBot - A Twitter bot that scan its account every five minutes for tweets received via mentions and in turn performs sentiment analysis on the twitter account specified in the mention. The Twitter bot then tweets a visualized sentiment analysis of the Twitter account's 500 most recent tweets. twitter.com/iPlotBot

Education and Poverty - A responsive visual analysis of the correlation between poverty and education in the United States. aizzakatrina.com/education_and_poverty

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accounting Analyst. Origin House. Santa Rosa, CA. 2018-2019 Staff Accountant. The RealReal Inc. San Francisco, CA. 2017–2018 Junior Accountant. The RealReal Inc. San Francisco, CA. 2015–2017 Accounting Associate. Stay Winning Boutique. Fremont, CA. 2014–2015

Bookkeeper. McCaulous Inc. Napa, CA. 2012

Student Assistant. Department of Human Development and Women's Studies. California State University, East Bay. 2012

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Promoter and Coordinator. Urban Women's Marketplace. Oakland, CA. 2014 Accounting Volunteer. Loved Twice. Oakland, CA. 2011–2013 Accounting Volunteer. Recovery Survival Network. San Francisco, CA. 2010